Secrets are buried just beneath the surface.
Where the Crawdads Sing is a drama, mystery,
romance film directed by Olivia Newman.
Abandoned by her family, Kya raises herself all alone in
the marshes outside of her small town.
When her former boyfriend is found dead, Kya is instantly branded by the local
townspeople and law enforcement as the prime suspect for his murder.
Kya Clark, played by Daisy Edgar-Jones.
Tate Walker, played by Taylor John Smith.
Chase Andrews, played by Harris Dickinson.
Tom Milton, played by David Strathairn.
Mabel, played by Michael Hyatt.
Jumpin', played by Sterling Macer Jr..
Where the Crawdads Sing is a 2022 American mystery drama film directed by Olivia
Newman and written by Lucy Alibar, based on the 2018 novel by Delia Owens.
The film stars Daisy Edgar-Jones, Taylor John Smith, Harris Dickinson, Michael Hyatt, Sterling
Macer Jr., Jojo Regina, Garret Dillahunt, Ahna O'Reilly, and David Strathairn.
The story follows Kya, an abandoned yet defiant girl, who raises herself to adulthood
in a North Carolina marshland, becoming a naturalist in the process.
When the town's hotshot is found dead, she is the
prime suspect and is tried for murder.
Mychael Danna composed the film's soundtrack, which includes
the original song "Carolina" by Taylor Swift.
The song won an MTV Movie & TV Award and was nominated for various other accolades,
including a Critics' Choice Award, a Golden Globe, a Grammy, and a Satellite Award.
Where the Crawdads Sing was released in the United States on
July 15, 2022, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised Edgar-Jones's
performance but found the film's overall tone incoherent.
The film was a box office success, grossing $144.3
million against a $24 million budget.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
artist, bullying, alcoholism, coming of age.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.